The world will know his name and the truth.
Richard Jewell is a drama, history film directed by Clint Eastwood.
Richard Jewell thinks quick, works fast, and saves hundreds, perhaps thousands, of lives after a domestic terrorist plants several pipe bombs
and they explode during a concert, only to be falsely suspected of the crime by sloppy FBI work and sensational media coverage.
Richard Jewell, played by Paul Walter Hauser.
Tom Shaw, played by Jon Hamm.
Bobi Jewell, played by Kathy Bates.
Watson Bryant, played by Sam Rockwell.
Kathy Scruggs, played by Olivia Wilde.
Nadya, played by Nina Arianda.
Richard Jewell is a 2019 American biographical drama film directed and
produced by Clint Eastwood and written by Billy Ray.
It is based on the 1997 Vanity Fair article "American Nightmare: The Ballad of Richard Jewell" by Marie Brenner and the 2019 book The Suspect:
An Olympic Bombing, the FBI, the Media, and Richard Jewell, the Man Caught in the Middle by Kent Alexander and Kevin Salwen.
The film depicts the July 27, 1996, Centennial Olympic Park bombing and its aftermath, as security guard Richard Jewell finds a bomb during the 1996
Summer Olympics in Atlanta, Georgia, and alerts authorities to evacuate, only to later be wrongly accused of having placed the device himself.
Paul Walter Hauser stars as Jewell, supported by Sam
Rockwell, Kathy Bates, Jon Hamm, and Olivia Wilde.
After its world premiere on November 20, 2019, at AFI Fest, the film was
theatrically released in the United States on December 13 by Warner Bros.
It grossed $44 million against a $45 million budget and received generally positive reviews from critics, with praise
for the performances (particularly those of Bates, Rockwell, and Hauser) and Eastwood's direction.
However, several journalists criticized the film's portrayal of the reporter who first accused
Jewell, Kathy Scruggs, specifically its depiction of her trading sex for stories.
Richard Jewell was chosen by the National Board of Review as one of the ten best films of the year, and for her performance in the film Bates won the National
Board of Review Award for Best Supporting Actress and was nominated for Best Supporting Actress at both the Academy Awards and the Golden Globes.
The film explores themes of biography, based on true story,
standard police procedure, cautionary tale.
The tone is emotional.